<doc sitename="Writer's Resource Blog" title="Writing as a Business" author="Laine Cunningham" date="2013-01-16" description="Posts about essay written by Laine Cunningham" categories="Agents;Marketing;Writing Tips;Conferences;Workshop;Contests, Grants and Awards;Literary Magazines" tags="Publishing;book agent;books;children's book;essay;fiction;flash fiction;marketing;nonfiction;novel;novella;writing;conference;juvenile;literary magazine;short story;workshop;award;contest" fingerprint="6606c055e9a56a48">
  <main>
    <div>
      <p>
        <hi rend="#b">Writing the Perfect Query Letter with Laine Cunningham, presented by Alice Osborn</hi>
      </p>
      <p>
        <hi rend="#b">Location: Center for Excellence, 3803-B Computer Dr. Suite 106, Raleigh, NC 27609</hi>
      </p>
      <p>
        <hi rend="#b">Saturday, March 9 Time: 1:30-4:30pm</hi>
      </p>
      <p>
        <hi rend="#b">Fee: $55 (Early Bird till March 1<hi rend="#sup">st</hi>)/$75 after</hi>
      </p>
      <p>
        <hi rend="#b">Registration: Click here </hi>
      </p>
      <p>Your query letter<hi rend="#b"/>is every bit as important as the opening pages of your novel. It’s your first opportunity to show your writing skills to a prospective agent or editor. Make it count! Make it shine! A good query letter should make that editor and agent want to read your material…and it should grab their hearts in the thirty seconds or so they give each query in their pile. In this class, publishing consultant and owner of the Writer’s Resource Laine Cunningham will discuss the three important elements to inject into your query so you can get published. Fiction and nonfiction authors writing books, stories or articles will benefit from this class.</p>
      <p>Laine Cunningham’s clients consistently garner attention from the nation’s top publishers and agents. Several of her clients’ books have been shopped around Hollywood and have received film options. She has been quoted on <hi rend="#i">CNN Money</hi>, <hi rend="#i">Media Bistro</hi>, and <hi rend="#i">The Writer Magazine</hi> for her opinion on the end of the Harry Potter series, the “Oprah Effect,” and Sarah Palin’s ghostwriter. She has presented workshops and lectures for The Loft, the nation’s largest independent literary organization; the National Writer’s Union; The Writer’s Workshop in Asheville and writing conferences across the country.</p>
      <div>
        <div>
          <div>
            <head rend="h3">Check out this cool blog post for readers and writers!</head>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div>
          <head rend="h3">Like this:</head>
          <p>Like Loading...</p>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div>
  </main>
  <comments/>
</doc>