<doc fingerprint="974495d9493c9ad4">
  <main>
    <p>Grooming is for everybody and men can’t be too lenient with their skincare. Women are inherently proactive about their grooming and skincare needs, but men need that extra push. If you are that guy who is still using a soap bar, you need to stop buddy!</p>
    <p>Not that there is a lack of evidence of how harsh can be the cleaning ingredients in the soap for the supple face skin, but men are deceived by their false sense of machoism. We strongly advise you to switch to face wash for a healthy and fresh glow on your face.</p>
    <p>GreatBuyz reviewed over 30 best face washes for men to pick the top 10. Don’t worry you can trust our judgment as we looked for products for every skin type before listing them here.</p>
    <p>Here are the top 10 scrutinized and tested best face washes for men in India.</p>
    <head rend="h1">Top 10 Face Wash for Men in India</head>
    <head rend="h2">1. Cetaphil Gentle Skin Cleanser</head>
    <p>Men with sensitive skin always have a hard time finding the right face wash, but not anymore. The Cetaphil Gentle Skin Cleanser is a face wash that is recommended by dermatologists for over 70 years.</p>
    <p>What makes it a good face wash is its soap-free formulation. Its creamy texture not only hydrates the skin on your face but also strengthens its moisture barrier. It is made with the help of micellar technology that empowers it to remove the deepest impurities from your skin.</p>
    <p>With this face wash, you can maintain the pH balance, preserve natural oils, and keep your skin pores unclogged while gently cleansing it.</p>
    <p>
      <hi rend="#b">Pros:</hi>
    </p>
    <list rend="ul">
      <item>Dermatologically tested</item>
      <item>Suitable for sensitive skin</item>
      <item>No irritation</item>
      <item>Improves skin texture</item>
      <item>Hydrates skin</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      <hi rend="#b">Cons:</hi>
    </p>
    <list rend="ul">
      <item>Consistency might be too thick for some</item>
    </list>
    <head rend="h2">2. Nivea Men Oil Control All In 1 Face Wash</head>
    <p>For those of you who have oily skin, Nivea has the solution. The Nivea Men Oil Control All In 1 face wash solve multiple problems including excess oil, acne, and dark spots. Common problem men with oily skin have to endure is rough texture but the multi-effect oil control cleansing formula of this face wash gives a smooth, refreshed and radiantly hydrated skin. This product is simply the best face wash for men’s oily skin.</p>
    <p>For a deeper cleaning of pores and removal of blackheads and whiteheads, it has a cooling mud formula. For long-lasting oil control face wash, there is no better alternative than Nivea Men Oil Control All In 1 Face Wash.</p>
    <p>
      <hi rend="#b">Pros:</hi>
    </p>
    <list rend="ul">
      <item>Natural charcoal formula deep cleanses and removes excess oils</item>
      <item>Long-lasting oil control effect</item>
      <item>Reduces dark spots</item>
      <item>Prevents and reduces acne</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      <hi rend="#b">Cons:</hi>
    </p>
    <list rend="ul">
      <item>Some men complain about the smell</item>
      <item>Can leave skin too dry</item>
    </list>
    <head rend="h2">3. Garnier Men Face Wash Power White Double Action</head>
    <p>If fairer skin is what you want, then the Garnier Men’s first Dual Texture face wash is for you. The dullness and dark tone are a result of dead cells and pollution accumulation on the face. To make men’s skin fairer, the formula in this face wash is supplemented by salicylic acid and vitamin C to deeply exfoliate your skin. It also contains charcoal and clay that help remove access oil from the face.</p>
    <p>
      <hi rend="#b">Pros:</hi>
    </p>
    <list rend="ul">
      <item>Enriched with salicylic active and vitamin C</item>
      <item>Best exfoliates oily skin</item>
      <item>Makes skin lighter</item>
      <item>Charcoal ingredients rejuvenate skin</item>
      <item>Works on acne-prone skin</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      <hi rend="#b">Cons:</hi>
    </p>
    <list rend="ul">
      <item>Not suitable for sensitive skin</item>
    </list>
    <head rend="h2">4. WOW Skin Science Apple Cider Vinegar Foaming Face Wash</head>
    <p>A face wash for all skin types, the WOW Skin Science Apple Cider Vinegar Foaming Face Wash is completely organic. Most face washes that are available have parabens, silicones, and sulphates in them, but this product has no such element.</p>
    <p>We put this in the top bracket of face washes for men as its bio-active formula of pure apple cider vinegar, Vitamins B5 and E, and aloe vera extract offer many health benefits. No matter what skin type you have, such a potent natural combination leaves no scope for dirty skin. If you are suffering from acne breakouts or want to remove marks on your skin, this is the face wash we recommend.</p>
    <p>
      <hi rend="#b">Pros: </hi>
    </p>
    <list rend="ul">
      <item>Suitable for all skin types</item>
      <item>Entirely organic formulation</item>
      <item>Apple cider vinegar has anti-bacterial properties</item>
      <item>Hyaluronic acid reduces fine lines and wrinkles</item>
      <item>Natural vitamin E fixes blemishes, scars, and damaged skin</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      <hi rend="#b">Cons:</hi>
    </p>
    <list rend="ul">
      <item>The smell is too strong</item>
    </list>
    <head rend="h2">5. Himalaya MEN Power Glow Licorice Face Wash</head>
    <p>The brand doesn’t need an introduction. For over 200 years, Himalaya is making the secrets of Ayurveda available for us in their skincare products. This is why you can trust the MEN Power Glow Licorice Face Wash to be the best men’s face wash for combination skin.</p>
    <p>The problem with combination skin is, the ingredients of a targeted face wash can do more harm than good. However, this soap-free Himalaya face wash is a natural product that cleans combination skin without harming its glow and suppleness.</p>
    <p>
      <hi rend="#b">Pros:</hi>
    </p>
    <list rend="ul">
      <item>Suitable for all skin types</item>
      <item>Blend of alfalfa, licorice, and wood apple brightens the complexion</item>
      <item>Menthol reduces inflammation or redness</item>
      <item>Acts as gentle exfoliate</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      <hi rend="#b">Cons:</hi>
    </p>
    <list rend="ul">
      <item>Not for fixing acne outbreak</item>
    </list>
    <head rend="h2">6. Mamaearth Vitamin C Face Wash for Men</head>
    <p>Mamaearth might not be the brand you think of when you are looking for men’s skincare products, but then you will miss an assortment of natural products made for men.</p>
    <p>The Mamaearth Vitamin C Face Wash has all-natural ingredients such as cucumber extract, turmeric extract, Vitamin C, and aloe vera. With no soap content, this face wash can gently cleanse any skin type and keep it hydrated. Furthermore, the turmeric extract reverses signs of aging in men while cucumber preserves skin’s elasticity and aloe vera prevents inflammation.</p>
    <p>
      <hi rend="#b">Pros: </hi>
    </p>
    <list rend="ul">
      <item>Suitable for all skin types</item>
      <item>Reverses sun damage</item>
      <item>Lightens pigmentation and acne marks</item>
      <item>No chemical ingredients</item>
      <item>A silicone cleanser brush included</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      <hi rend="#b">Cons:</hi>
    </p>
    <list rend="ul">
      <item>Expensive than other natural face washes for men</item>
    </list>
    <head rend="h2">7. Neutrogena Oil-Free Acne Wash for Men</head>
    <p>This Oil-Free Acne Wash from Neutrogena is a remarkable product for spotless skin. Due to the presence of salicylic acid, this face wash is highly effective on acne-prone skin. The 2% salicylic acid present in this face wash not only controls outbreaks but also helps remove acne marks.</p>
    <p>The MICROCLEAR® technology used in this product makes it easier to clean pores and unclog them without using alcohol.</p>
    <p>
      <hi rend="#b">Pros: </hi>
    </p>
    <list rend="ul">
      <item>Best for acne-prone skin</item>
      <item>Maintains the pH balance of the skin</item>
      <item>Removes excess oil without making the skin dry</item>
      <item>Easy application due to pump bottle</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      <hi rend="#b">Cons:</hi>
    </p>
    <list rend="ul">
      <item>Not suited for dry or sensitive skin</item>
    </list>
    <head rend="h2">8. Ponds Men Energy Bright Anti-Dullness Face Wash</head>
    <p>If you are looking for face wash for men’s fairness, Pond’s Men Energy Bright Face Wash is going to amaze you. This face wash is formulated to provide instant brightness as it removes grime and impurities from the skin at the cell level. It removes all signs of pollution removing dirt, oil, and dead skin cells.</p>
    <p>It has a 2-in-1 power formulation of coffee bean extract and cooling menthol. The coffee bean extract provides instant brightness while the cooling menthol refreshes the skin and also controls inflammation.</p>
    <p>
      <hi rend="#b">Pros:</hi>
    </p>
    <list rend="ul">
      <item>Suitable for oily skin</item>
      <item>Anti-dullness and brightening face wash</item>
      <item>No parabens and silicones</item>
      <item>Gel-based face wash</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      <hi rend="#b">Cons: </hi>
    </p>
    <list rend="ul">
      <item>Not suitable for sensitive skin</item>
    </list>
    <head rend="h2">9. Gentle Beast Premium Activated Charcoal Face Wash</head>
    <p>If you spend a lot of your time outdoors, then you will need the efficient cleansing of activated charcoal. The Gentle Beast Premium Activated Charcoal Face Wash is for active men who love to sweat and get dirty while living an active lifestyle.</p>
    <p>Packed with the goodness of neem, aloe vera, cucumber, charcoal, and green tea extract, this organic and soap-free face wash is suitable for all skin types. This face wash not only cleanses the skin but also controls oil production, smoothens texture, removes tan and puffiness, and keeps face skin moisturized and supple.</p>
    <p>
      <hi rend="#b">Pros:</hi>
    </p>
    <list rend="ul">
      <item>Suitable for all skin types</item>
      <item>No silicones and parabens</item>
      <item>Cleanses as well as detoxifies the skin</item>
      <item>Reverses signs of aging</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      <hi rend="#b">Cons:</hi>
    </p>
    <list rend="ul">
      <item>Expensive</item>
    </list>
    <head rend="h2">10. L’Oreal Paris Men Expert White Activ Brightening Foam</head>
    <p>We conclude our list of the best face wash for men in India with a L’Oreal product. The Men Expert White Activ intensive whitening foam as the name suggests is an excellent skin whitening face wash for men. The pro-exfoliating formula not only removes the dead cells from the skin but also stimulates a dead skin-cell removal cycle leaving the skin luminous and bright.</p>
    <p>
      <hi rend="#b">Pros: </hi>
    </p>
    <list rend="ul">
      <item>Suitable for oily skin</item>
      <item>Active defence system helps skin reinforce natural resistance against daily aggressions</item>
      <item>Pro exfoliation, a powerful peeling agent stimulates natural dead skin cell removal</item>
      <item>Gently cleanses skin</item>
      <item>Instantly brightens skin</item>
    </list>
    <p>
      <hi rend="#b">Cons:</hi>
    </p>
    <list rend="ul">
      <item>Can leave the skin dry</item>
    </list>
    <head rend="h1">
      <hi rend="#b">Conclusion</hi>
    </head>
    <p>There is no alternative to regular skincare if you want to look young and energetic. We hope these top 10 face washes for men in India will help you keep your face healthy and fresh-looking.</p>
    <p>Do let us know how was your experience with these products.</p>
    <head rend="h1">FAQ</head>
    <p>Q. How to choose the right face wash?</p>
    <p>Maybe we made it easy for you to pick the best face wash for men, still, you must be aware of the factors to check before selecting a product.</p>
    <p>Q How to select the right facewash for Oily skin?</p>
    <p>The oily skin is the trickiest to manage. Due to excess sebum production, the moisture is held in the skin which makes it dull and clogs pores causing acne. Dermatologists suggest face washes with salicylic acid or lactic acid for oily skin.</p>
    <p>Q. How to select the right facewash for Dry skin?</p>
    <p>If you have dry skin, then you must avoid face washes with alcohols, sodium lauryl sulfate, triclosan, salicylic acid, and glycolic acid. Pick milk or gel-based face washes that preserve natural skin oils.</p>
    <p>Q. How to select the right facewash for Sensitive/Combination skin?</p>
    <p>Sensitive and combination skin is easily irritated and requires chemical-free face washes with ingredients like aloe, chamomile, and green tea polyphenols. Such soothing ingredients keep the skin healthy.</p>
    <p>Q. How to select the right facewash for Normal skin?</p>
    <p>Normal skin is easiest to manage so you can try a face wash that is suitable for all skin types.</p>
    <p>Q. How often should men wash their face?</p>
    <p>Generally speaking, washing your face twice a day, once in the morning and once at night, is enough for most men. You will risk drying your skin if you do it any more often. Although a splash of water in the afternoon is alright for men with oily skin.</p>
  </main>
  <comments/>
</doc>